Matthew Koenigs

Frontend Engineer

624 SE 26th Terrace, Cape Coral, FL 33904 | Telephone: (239) 209-4278 | Email: MattKoenigs@live.com

Objective

To obtain a career opportunity where I can continue to advance my skillset and improve efficiency within every project to benefit the team and company.

Summary of Qualifications

Over the past 25 years, I have built relationships with industry-leading companies such as ABC, NBC, AP, CNN, AWS, WorldNow, Akamai, Limelight and Salesforce. I have gained experience in SQL Development, SEO optimization and using CMS systems including Oracle ATG, Ad Delivery systems including DART/DFP and Adagogo as well as analytics and scripting platforms including GA and GTM. I am also proficient with programs such as Visual Studio Code, Adobe Photoshop and Microsoft Office products.

Work Experience

July 2020 – Present

Frontend Engineer - Chicos FAS

Fort Myers, FL

- > Participate in all phases of the software development cycle, including development, design and testing through agile scrum process.
- Lead dev on all brands' Loyalty/Rewards programs which continue to bring in more sales to our sites by driving more traffic to our sites from our existing customer base.
- > Lead dev for launching pixels from our various third-party vendors within our GTM and ensuring they give as minimal impact to our sites' loadtime as possible.

June 2014 - July 2020

Web Developer - Chicos FAS

Fort Myers, FL

- Developing and scheduling Homepages, custom landing pages and promos ahead of schedule with data tracking for Analytics.
- Lead dev for all Social Web Developing (FBML, Twitter API, YouTube, Pinterest, Instagram and G+).

July 2009 - June 2014

Senior Web Developer & Online Ad Manager - Waterman Broadcasting Corp.

Fort Myers, FL

- Management of inter-department projects and coordinating with multiple vendors
- > Developing mobile websites specially formatted for iOS, Android, Microsoft Phone, etc.
- Creating, scheduling and reporting of all digital ads across our multiple websites and mobile apps.

March 2005 - June 2009

Web Manager & Graphic Ad Creator - Waterman Broadcasting Corp.

Fort Myers, FL

- > Setup and maintaining databases and data used on company websites
- Creating, scheduling and reporting all digital advertising across our multiple websites.

March 2000 - March 2005

Web Developer - Waterman Broadcasting Corp.

Fort Myers, FL

- Designing, improving and providing ongoing technical support for nbc-2.com and abc-7.com
- Programming redesigns of the company web sites to accommodate high-demand for essential information during major news and weather events including hurricanes and elections.

Education

1994 - 1998

Florida State University

Tallahassee, FL

- B.S. in Information Studies
 - Learned basic skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and CGI/Perl scripting.
- Minors in Psychology and International Affairs